ARINDRA KUMAR DAS

April 3, 2017

ABOUT ME

I am a Human Computer Interaction (HCI) Professional. I have experience in many different aspects of HCI and Design which involves User Experience Design, User Research, User Interface Design, Graphic Designer and Animator, Front-end developer and Product developer.

I have academic background with 3 Master's degree from some of the top Universities and reputed research groups in the fields of Computer Science, Cognitive Psychology, Entrepreneurship and Electronics and Communication Engineering.

I have, over the years, worked with high-tech companies like Microsoft services, Ericsson research, Nokia and ABB. I have served as an interim VP/Chief product/UX designer to many early stage startups. I am also mentoring various London Startups with their Product Design.

I have a wide range of experience in building digital products across different demographics (kids to older adults). I follow user-centred approach with an amalgam of lean and agile methodology. I gained my experience from both academics as well as professional experience.

You could read some of my research papers (on the topics such as UX, Neural networks(AI), emotions, Blockchain etc.) in here.

In my free-time I also build rules/tools/libraries/icons etc. to make my design process smoother and quicker, such as here.

P.S. I am happy to show my work in-person, however, some of my old projects are here.

EDUCATION

INTERACTION DESIGN FOUNDATION

PROFESSIONAL
EDUCATION IN USER
EXPERIENCE AND
INTERACTION DESIGN

DUAL DEGREE: UCL UNIVERSITY AND KTH UNIVERSITY

MSc. IN ICT INNOVATION Specialization in Human Computer Interaction and Design

AALTO UNIVERSITY (HELSINKI UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY)

MSc. Communication Engineering (WITH DISTINCTION)

SRM UNIVERSITY

B.Tech Electronics and Communication Engineering (First Class)

SKILLS

DESIGN & PROTOTYPE

PAPER PROTOTYPING, SKETCH APP, HTML, CSS, JQUERY, BOOTSTRAP, JAVASCRIPT, POWERPOINT, KEYNOTE, BALSAMIQ, MARVEL, INVISIONAPP, ARDUINO, PHOTOSHOP (GIMP)

OTHERS

VISUALISATION, EXPERT & PARTICIPANT-BASED EVALUATION, USER-CENTRED DESIGN, EMOTIONAL DESIGN, PERSONAS, USER SCENARIOS, TASK ANALYSIS, CONTEXTUAL ANALYSIS, ANTHROPOMETRY, WORKSPACE DESIGN, QUALITATIVE ANALYSIS, INTERVIEWS, OBSERVATIONS, FOCUS GROUPS

EXPERIENCE

KONSILEO | Design (UX) LEAD (CONSULTANT)

August 2016 - Present | London, UK

Konsileo is an insurance tech startup that is revolutionizing the Insurance broking industry. I am working with the CEO, CTO, Marketing Lead and Product Owner to help conceptualize their product ideas as well as working on their branding, UX and UI.

LOCPIN | LEAD UX (CONSULTANT)

March 2017 - Present | London, UK

Working with the CEO to help conceptualize and build the initial MVP and bring their product to live.

ONKHO | UX and Front-end (Consultant)

March 2017 - Present | London, UK

Onkho is a SAAS-based accountancy startup and I joined there last minute (Beta release April) to fix their design and validate before the release.

MASSCHALLENGE | MENTOR AND JUDGE (PRODUCT AND USER EXPERIENCE)

July 2015 - Present | London, UK

MassChallenge is world's largest non-profit accelerator. I advise MassChallenge startups with product design and user experience. I am also the part of judging panel to select the top 90 startups from across the world out of 1500+ applications. So far I have advised the following startups:

- WeTrack (wetrack.com): Project management software to manage large scale events.
- TwoSigmas (twosigmas.com): An online platform connecting educators with students through personal tutoring.
- **Metadrift (metadrift.io):** Using Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Virtual Reality (VR) to transform video archives into immersive learning platforms.
- Monizo (monizo.com): A bank account for freelancers to manage their money and taxes efficiently.
- Firesouls (firesouls.co.uk): A SaaS marketplace that uses public procurement to match resources with local communities.

GREENSEED | Co founder & Head of Product

Oct 2014 - March 2016 | London, UK

A platform for people interested in growing food to connect, learn, inspire and eventually sell-swap products. Doing all things, startup (Product, User Experience, User Interface, Growth marketing, Strategy & investment).

DOCUVO | INTERIM VP PRODUCT DESIGN

Nov 2015 - July 2016 | London, UK

• Docuvo is creating the next generation Document management system. I was responsible for leading the branding and product design for the start-up.

STARTUPBOOTCAMP FINTECH | Entrepreneur-in-Residence (Product design)

July 2015 - Nov 2015 | London, UK

- Provided support and advise on Product design, User experience and applying Agile and Lean startup methodologies to 9 Fintech startups from 6 different nations.
- Conducted a workshop with startups on Lean User Experience and best practices for Product Design.
- Some of my contributions:
 - 1. Delio (deliowealth.com): Helped to built the first prototype for their investment platform.

LINKS

Github:// arindrakumardas LinkedIn:// arindradas Twitter:// @nomadiccreature

- 2. StockViews (stockviews.com): Advised on their complete app and coded their customer on-boarding process.
- 3. Worapay (worapay.com): Designed all their marketing materials while piloting with Llyods bank.
- 4. Cybertonica (cybertonica.com): Designed and developed their Website.
- 5. BondIT (bonditglobal.com): Evaluated their portfolio management app.
- 6. Tradle (tradle.io): Advised on their product design as well as helped them with their investment deck.

FIREFLY | UX CONSULTANT

Oct 2015 - Mar 2016 | London, UK

• I worked to wireframe their marketplace and dashboard feature. I ran card sorting sessions to categories the important POIs for the app.

MICROSOFT | USER RESEARCHER

Dec 2014 - Sep 2015 | London, UK

 (Part of UCL's strategic industrial partnership under the supervision of Dr. Nadia Berthouze) The project aims to understand how technology can be used by carers to better respond and manage the needs of elderly people in a more efficient and effective way.

COMIC RELIEF | UX CONSULTANT

Nov 2014 - Dec 2014 | London, UK

- Contractual work to conduct website evaluation for the British charity, Comic Relief (http://www.comicrelief.com)
- Recruited, facilitated and analyzed results for A/B testing of alternative designs for the Comic Relief website
- Provided usability insights and design recommendations to the Comic Relief team

AALTO UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF SCIENCE | GAME DESIGNER

May 2012 - Aug 2015 | Helsinki, Finland & Remote

- Conceptualize and built a business simulation game
- Responsibility included front-end development, User research, User interface and Evaluation.

ERICSSON RESEARCH | RESEARCHER

Nov 2012 – Aug 2013 | Helsinki, Finland

- Proposed a case for enterprise collaboration with IMS, Microsoft Lync and WebRTC for arbitrary datatypes
- Visualization of Cloud Media Server (CMS)

ABB & AALTO DESIGN FACTORY | PRODUCT DESIGNER

Nov 2012 – Aug 2013 | Helsinki, Finland

- Product designer to develop a sales and marketing tool with Android for ABB sales people.
- Collaborating the Human factors, UI design team and Scrum team.
- Research on new technology and knowledge on HVAC ACH550 drives by ABB